<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY legal SYSTEM "legal.xml">
<!ENTITY appversion "2.28">
<!ENTITY manrevision "1.0">
<!ENTITY date "July 2009">
<!ENTITY app "<application>Lights Off</application>">
<!ENTITY appname "Lights Off">
<!ENTITY version "1.0">
]>
<!-- 
      (Do not remove this comment block.)
  Maintained by the GNOME Documentation Project
  http://developer.gnome.org/projects/gdp
  Template version: 2.0 beta
  Template last modified Feb 12, 2002
-->
<!-- =============Document Header ============================= -->
<article id="index" lang="sl">
<!-- please do not change the id; for translations, change lang to -->
<!-- appropriate code -->
  <articleinfo>
    <title>Priročnik igre <application>Ugasni  luči</application></title>

    <abstract role="description">
      <para>
	Lights Off is a puzzle game, where the objective is to turn off all
	of the tiles on the board. Each click toggles the state of the
	clicked tile and its non-diagonal neighbors.
      </para>
    </abstract>

    <copyright>
      <year>2010</year>
      <holder>Tim Horton</holder>
    </copyright>

  <!-- translators: uncomment this:

  <copyright>
   <year>2000</year>
   <holder>ME-THE-TRANSLATOR (Latin translation)</holder>
  </copyright>

   -->
<!-- An address can be added to the publisher information.  If a role is 
     not specified, the publisher/author is the same for all versions of the 
     document.  -->
    <publisher> 
      <publishername>Projekt dokumentacije GNOME</publishername> 
    </publisher> 

     <legalnotice id="legalnotice">
	<para>
	  Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this
	  document under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation
	  License (GFDL), Version 1.1 or any later version published
	  by the Free Software Foundation with no Invariant Sections,
	  no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts.  You can find
	  a copy of the GFDL at this <ulink type="help" url="ghelp:fdl">link</ulink> or in the file COPYING-DOCS
	  distributed with this manual.
         </para>
         <para> This manual is part of a collection of GNOME manuals
          distributed under the GFDL.  If you want to distribute this
          manual separately from the collection, you can do so by
          adding a copy of the license to the manual, as described in
          section 6 of the license.
	</para>

	<para>
	  Many of the names used by companies to distinguish their
	  products and services are claimed as trademarks. Where those
	  names appear in any GNOME documentation, and the members of
	  the GNOME Documentation Project are made aware of those
	  trademarks, then the names are in capital letters or initial
	  capital letters.
	</para>

	<para>
	  DOCUMENT AND MODIFIED VERSIONS OF THE DOCUMENT ARE PROVIDED
	  UNDER  THE TERMS OF THE GNU FREE DOCUMENTATION LICENSE
	  WITH THE FURTHER UNDERSTANDING THAT:

	  <orderedlist>
		<listitem>
		  <para>DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS,
                    WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR
                    IMPLIED, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, WARRANTIES
                    THAT THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE
                    DOCUMENT IS FREE OF DEFECTS MERCHANTABLE, FIT FOR
                    A PARTICULAR PURPOSE OR NON-INFRINGING. THE ENTIRE
                    RISK AS TO THE QUALITY, ACCURACY, AND PERFORMANCE
                    OF THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE
                    DOCUMENT IS WITH YOU. SHOULD ANY DOCUMENT OR
                    MODIFIED VERSION PROVE DEFECTIVE IN ANY RESPECT,
                    YOU (NOT THE INITIAL WRITER, AUTHOR OR ANY
                    CONTRIBUTOR) ASSUME THE COST OF ANY NECESSARY
                    SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION. THIS DISCLAIMER
                    OF WARRANTY CONSTITUTES AN ESSENTIAL PART OF THIS
                    LICENSE. NO USE OF ANY DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED
                    VERSION OF THE DOCUMENT IS AUTHORIZED HEREUNDER
                    EXCEPT UNDER THIS DISCLAIMER; AND
		  </para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		  <para>UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES AND UNDER NO LEGAL
                       THEORY, WHETHER IN TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE),
                       CONTRACT, OR OTHERWISE, SHALL THE AUTHOR,
                       INITIAL WRITER, ANY CONTRIBUTOR, OR ANY
                       DISTRIBUTOR OF THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION
                       OF THE DOCUMENT, OR ANY SUPPLIER OF ANY OF SUCH
                       PARTIES, BE LIABLE TO ANY PERSON FOR ANY
                       DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR
                       CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OF ANY CHARACTER
                       INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, DAMAGES FOR LOSS
                       OF GOODWILL, WORK STOPPAGE, COMPUTER FAILURE OR
                       MALFUNCTION, OR ANY AND ALL OTHER DAMAGES OR
                       LOSSES ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO USE OF THE
                       DOCUMENT AND MODIFIED VERSIONS OF THE DOCUMENT,
                       EVEN IF SUCH PARTY SHALL HAVE BEEN INFORMED OF
                       THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.
		  </para>
		</listitem>
	  </orderedlist>
	</para>
  </legalnotice>


   <!-- This file  contains link to license for the documentation (GNU FDL),
and 
        other legal stuff such as "NO WARRANTY" statement. Please do not change 
	any of this. -->
	
    <authorgroup> 
      <author role="maintainer"> 
	<firstname>Tim</firstname> 
	<surname>Horton</surname> 
	<affiliation> 
	  <address> <email>hortont@gnome.org</email> </address> 
	</affiliation> 
      </author> 
<!-- This is appropriate place for other contributors: translators,
      maintainers,  etc. Commented out by default.
       <othercredit role="translator">
	<firstname>Latin</firstname> 
	<surname>Translator 1</surname> 
	<affiliation> 
	  <orgname>Latin Translation Team</orgname> 
	  <address> <email>translator@gnome.org</email> </address> 
	</affiliation>
	<contrib>Latin translation</contrib>
      </othercredit>
-->
    </authorgroup>
	
	<releaseinfo revision="2.29" role="review"/>

    <revhistory>
      <revision> 
	<revnumber>Lights Off Manual V1.0</revnumber> 
	<date>januar 2010</date> 
	<revdescription> 
	  <para role="author">x</para>
	  <para role="publisher">Projekt dokumentacije GNOME</para>
	</revdescription> 
      </revision> 
    </revhistory> 

    <releaseinfo>This manual describes version 2.28 of Lights Off.
    </releaseinfo>
    <!-- The following feedback information only applies to applications
    listed in bugzilla.gnome.org and bugzilla.ximian.com. For other
    applications, please provide your own feedback info or remove this
    section altogether -->
    <legalnotice> 
      <title>Odziv</title> 
      <para>To report a bug or make a suggestion regarding the <application>Lights Off</application>
application or
	this manual, follow the directions in the 
	<ulink url="ghelp:user-guide?feedback-bugs" type="help">GNOME Feedback Page</ulink>. 
      </para>
<!-- Translators may also add here feedback address for translations -->
    </legalnotice>

  </articleinfo>

  <indexterm zone="index"> 
    <primary>Ugasni luči</primary> 
  </indexterm>

<!-- ==============================Document Body==================-->

<sect1 id="s1-intro">
 <title>Uvod</title>

<!--synopsis of game-->
  <para><application>Lights Off</application> is a puzzle game, where the objective is to turn off all of the tiles on the board. Each click toggles the state of the clicked tile and its non-diagonal neighbors.</para>

<!--running game-->
   <para>To run <application>Lights Off</application>, select <menuchoice><guimenu>Applications</guimenu><guisubmenu>Games</guisubmenu><guimenuitem>Lights Off</guimenuitem></menuchoice>, or type <command>lightsoff</command> in the command line.</para>

<!--part of gnome-games-->
   <para><application>Lights Off</application> is included in the <filename>gnome-games</filename> package, which is part of the GNOME desktop environment. This document describes version 1.0 of <application>Lights Off</application>.</para>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="s1-playing">
 <title>Playing <application>Lights Off</application></title>
  <para>You progress through the levels either by turning off all of the tiles in a particular level, or using the arrow-shaped buttons near the bottom of the game. These buttons allow you to skip levels, or return to previous levels, without restriction.</para>
   <sect2 id="s2-block-moving">
     <title> Manipulating the Board</title>
      <para>There is only one action available in <application>Lights Off</application>: clicking a tile on the board. You can either click on the tile with the mouse, or use the arrow keys to choose it. The first time you press an arrow key during a game of <application>Lights Off</application>, a cursor will appear, which you can move with the keyboard; pressing enter will click the light below the cursor.</para>
      <para>When a tile is clicked, both it and all of its non-diagonal neighbors will toggle their state. The objective is to turn all of the tiles on the board off.</para>
   </sect2>
   <sect2 id="s2-newgame">
     <title>Začetek nove igre</title>
      <para>To begin a new game, go to <menuchoice><guimenu>Game</guimenu><guimenuitem>New Game</guimenuitem></menuchoice>. The progression of levels will be the same between games and between computers, so <menuchoice><guimenuitem>New Game</guimenuitem></menuchoice> should only be chosen if you actually want to return to the beginning of the game.</para>
    </sect2>
</sect1>

 
<sect1 id="s1-customizegame">
 <title>Prilagajanje igre <application>Ugasni luči</application></title>
   <sect2 id="s2-customlook">
    <title>Prilagajanje videza igre <application>Ugasni luči</application></title>
    <para>Under <menuchoice><guimenu>Game</guimenu><guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem></menuchoice>, you can customize the look of the tiles in <application>Lights Off</application>. There are a variety of styles included, some of which make use of the color of your theme. This can be disabled with the <guilabel>Use colors from GNOME Theme</guilabel> option in the Preferences window.</para>
    </sect2>
   </sect1>

<sect1 id="authors">
  <title>Avtorji</title>
  <para>
   <application>Lights Off</application> was written by Tim Horton
   in 2009 and maintained by the Gnome Games Team since then. This manual was
   written by Tim Horton.
   To report a bug or make a suggestion regarding this application or
   this manual, follow the directions in this
   <ulink url="ghelp:user-guide?feedback-bugs" type="help">document</ulink>.
  </para>

  <!-- For translations: uncomment this:

  <para>
   Latin translation was done by ME
   (<email>MYNAME@MYADDRESS</email>). Please send all  comments  and
   suggestions regarding this translation to SOMEWHERE.
  </para>

  -->
</sect1>


 <!-- ============= Application License ============================= -->

 <sect1 id="s1-license">
  <title>Dovoljenje</title>
  <para>This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the  <citetitle><ulink type="help" url="gnome-help:gpl">GNU General Public License</ulink></citetitle> as published by the Free Software Foundation;  either version 2 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.
  </para>
  <para>This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the <citetitle>GNU General Public License</citetitle> for more details.
  </para>
  <para>A copy of the <citetitle>GNU General Public License</citetitle> is included as an appendix to the <citetitle>GNOME Users Guide</citetitle>.  You may also obtain a copy of the <citetitle>GNU General Public License</citetitle> from the Free Software Foundation by visiting <ulink type="http" url="http://www.fsf.org">their Web site</ulink> or by writing to
   <address>
    Free Software Foundation, Inc.
    <street>59 Temple Place</street> - Suite 330
    <city>Boston</city>, <state>MA</state> <postcode>02111-1307</postcode>
    <country>USA</country>
   </address>
  </para>
 </sect1>
</article>
